AMIT MANJARLY Software Developer

+91-7359586420 | amitmanjarly9@gmail.com | GitHub: Manjarly | LinkedIn: Amit Manjarly

Profile

A computer engineer with 2 years of industry experience with an urge to succeed as a full stack developer actively seeking a position as a **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** with an organization in need of a professional with technological skills, multitasking abilities, and drive to exceed corporate objectives

Education

L. J. Institute of Engineering and Technology - Ahmedabad, India (Gujarat Technological University)

2015 - 2019

Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Engineering - 8.19 CGPA

Shree Narayana Guru Vidhyalaya - Ahmedabad, India

2014 - 2015

12th – Science – 67.2%

Skills and Others

Technical Skills:

• SQL, Java, MySQL, Maven, Python, JDBC, C++, HTML, CSS, Data Structures and Algorithms

OS and Version Control:

Linux (CISCO – NDG Certified), Windows, Github

Development Methodologies and Tools:

Agile/Scrum, Kanban, JIRA, Eclipse

Soft Skills:

 Active Listening, Complex Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Inductive Reasoning, Information Ordering, Mathematical Reasoning, Selective Attention, Speech Clarity

Professional Experience

Associate Software Engineer – Accenture, Hyderabad

March, 2021 - Present

- Receiving business requirements as part of Waterfall development methodology resulting in creation of epics
- Creating logs of errors and test cases so that the bugs can be rectified before the release
- Performing Sanity/Manual/Functional/Regression testing for deployment from SIT to UAT
- Supporting in the PROD testing during the production release
- Validating the data in IMPALA, HIVE, ORACLE database such that the update is not affecting existing data
- Manually creating sample data to check additional negative test cases for better verification of code
- Providing the business and user with 100% satisfactory and desired results giving error free deployment

Front-End Developer Intern - TerminalTrend, Ahmedabad

January, 2021 - February, 2021

- Observed the development of real-time online shopping web-application
- · Worked on front-end web-applications using core JavaScript and back-end using NodeJS
- Created multiple front-end applications while learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript during my tenure

Academic Projects

Health and Fitness Web Application

- A PHP based web-application which suggested user exercise and diet based on their inputs
- Primarily worked on Oracle DB to manage all the user data
- Regularly optimised the SQL gueries for faster access to information as per user's requirement
- Suggested user links to external websites for exercise and diet for their BMI
- User had feasibility of getting proper guidance for his/her BMI on a single platform

Additional Information

Personally working on:

- Competitive programming on CodeForces, Google's CodeJam and KickStart, HackerRank
- Self learning Data Structures and Algorithms primarily on LeetCode, CodeForces and CodeChef
- YouTube channel where I explain and solve LeetCode questions (Link: Amit Manjarly)
- Learning Linux Kernel, MySQL, JDBC and Hibernate by self using online resources
- Uploading self solved solution of CodeForces to GitHub (Link: Manjarly)

Hobbies: I read books and I know things